A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Pupil Placement Board, 1957-1966
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Pupil Placement Board, 1957-1966
The Library of Virginia
26517
263.7 cu. ft (746 boxes)
Pupil Placement Board
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected information is considered closed for 75 years after date of record creation. Types of records restricted include but are not limited to: medical information, social security numbers, and student transcripts. Restricted material has been redacted and/or sealed but has not been removed from the collection.
Acquisition Information
Accession 26517 was transfered by the Virginia Pupil Placement Board, 29-30 June 1966.
Historical Information
The creation of Virginia's Pupil Placement Board was approved by an act of the Virginia General Assembly on September 29, 1956. The Pupil Placement Act was one part of a comprehensive package of legislation passed during the 1956 special session to negate and counteract the effects of the opinion expressed by the U.S. Supreme Court in Brown v. Board of Education (1954). The Brown decision marked the end of legal segregation in public schools by concluding that separate facilities for students of different races are inherently unequal and thus in violation of the fourteenth amendment to the U.S. Constitution. In 1955 the U.S. Supreme Court revisited the Brown decision to provide a timeline for the integration of pubic schools. The court left much room for interpretation by stating that schools should be integrated, "with all deliberate speed."
In response to the Brown cases, U.S. Senator Harry F. Byrd (D-Virginia) coined the term for what would become Virginia's overarching integration policy when he stated, "If we can organize the Southern States for massive resistance to this order I think that in time the rest of the country will realize that racial integration is not going to be accepted in the South." Virginia's "Massive Resistance" policy ran counter to the Supreme Court's order for public schools to integrate "with all deliberate speed" by using state law to hopelessly hinder integration and thus thwart the intent of the court.
The Pupil Placement Board, as one arm of the policy of Massive Resistance was charged with assigning, enrolling, or placing students to and in public schools. The Pupil Placement Board consisted of three members appointed by the Governor. Pupil placement was a task formerly under the control of school boards and division superintendents. The board's authorizing legislation required members to take several factors into consideration when placing a pupil in a school. Factors included but were not limited to the health of the pupil, his or her aptitudes, the availability of transportation, and, "such other relevant matters as may be pertinent to the efficient operation of the schools or indicate a clear and present danger to the public peace and tranquility affecting the safety or welfare of the citizens of such school district." Students who were already in school before the board's creation were not obligated to apply for placement. Thus, the board only oversaw the placement of students who sought to move from one school to another or who were applying to attend school for the first time.
In December of 1956, Governor Thomas B. Stanley appointed Hugh V. White, Beverly H. Randolph Jr., and Andrew A. Farley to serve as the Pupil Placement Board. White was employed as Superintendent of Schools for Nansemond County beginning in 1934, he also served as president of the Virginia Principals Association and on the Superintendent Advisory Committee to the State Superintendent of Public Institutions. Randolph, a Richmond City native and former member of the House of Delegates, who at the time of his placement board membership, was an attorney in Charles City County. Farley was the Vice President and General Manager of the Register Publishing Company in Danville, the company was responsible for the "Danville Register" and "Danville Bee," he also served on the State Board of Conservative Development. From the beginning the placement board was frustrated by legal challenges from federal courts and by local school boards that increasingly tended to ignore the board's decisions.
All three board members served from the board's creation until they tendered a collective resignation effective in early 1960. Their resignations followed an Act of the General Assembly approved on April 28, 1959 that returned the responsibility of pupil placement to localities. Speaking before the General Assembly On January 28, 1959, Governor James Lindsay Almond, Jr. spoke on behalf of the Pupil Placement Board and defended it against the charge that it served as an impediment to integration. However, Governor Almond concluded that Virginia must, "repeal...laws that have been finally adjudged to be unconstitutional or have proven ineffective." He added that Virginia must, "prepare for the future by removing from our statutes that which those who oppose our way of life have used as a virus to contaminate the whole." He urged the assembly to reconsider laws governing education, including laws governing the transfer of pupils from school to school.
Following the resignation of the board's membership, the Journal of the Senate enrolled House Joint Resolution 91 on March 10, 1960, acknowledging the board's mass resignation, "as a result of circumstances which would render their task almost impossible of performance." In July of 1960 the original members were replaced by Governor Almond with Earnest J. Oglesby, Edward T. Justis, and Alfred L. Wingo. Oglesby at the time of his appointment he was a professor of Mathematics at the University of Virginia. In Albemarle County he served on the Board of Trustees at the Miller school, as well as, the President of the Defenders of State Sovereignty and Individual Liberties (a segregationist organization begun in Petersburg which proposed to become an advocacy group for whites much as the NAACP had done for African Americans). Justis, a Chesterfield County native worked as a science teacher and director of athletics at Chester High School and principal of Midlothian High School before joining the Department of Education in 1942, where he was eventually named Assistant State Supervisor of Rehabilitation. Wingo, born in Amelia County; worked as a counselor at Farmville State Teaching College before becoming Conductor of Guidance, Testing, Research and Surveys for the Department of Education in 1944. Even with the loss of most of its power and the effective end of the "Massive Resistance" movement in 1959, the Pupil Placement Board remained in existence for another seven years until it was finally abolished by an act of the General Assembly in 1966.
Scope and Content
This collection includes, but is not limited to, incoming and outgoing correspondence, memorandums, maps, reports, trail transcripts, personnel files, applications, transfer requests, calendars and newspaper clippings. Correspondents include, but are not limited to, parents, school superintendents, school principals, and school boards. Topics discussed include: policies and procedures, desegregation, education laws, student records, demography, and supreme court decisions. Each series is described in more detail within the finding aid.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files
Series II: Personnel Records
Series III: Minutes
Series IV: Legal Files
Series V: Publications
Series VI: Maps
Series VII: Applications
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1957-1966., Extent: 20.75 cu. ft. (62 boxes) (Box 1-62)
  - Subseries I. General, 1957-1966., 1.05 cu. ft. (5 boxes) (Box 1-5)
    The bulk of this subseries contains routine correspondence of the Pupil Placement Board, such as, memorandums to and from board members, information regarding applications, the student assignment process, and desegregation plans developed by school boards throughout the state. Of particular interest in this subseries are letters written in support and condemnation of segregation.
    Arragned alphabetically by folder title.
    - "A Farewell Ode" A Poem by Getchen Boyd, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Applicants (For summer position), 1957-1966. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Application Forms, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Application - Sample, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arlington Office, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Authorized Signatures, 1957-1966. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Birth Records, 1957-1966. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board Members, 1957-1966. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board Members - Bland, Joseph W., 1957-1958. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Board Members - Farley, Andrew, 1957. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board Members - Hilton, Birshell S., 1959-1963. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Board Members - Justis, Edward T., 1962-1966. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Board Members - Oglesby, E. J., 1961 - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Board Members - Randolph, Beverley, Jr., 1957. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Board Member - White, Hugh, 1957-1960. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Board Members - Wingo, A. L., 1962. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Civil Rights Committee - Applications, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Civil Rights Conference - Williamsburg, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Court Orders List, 1957-1966. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Daily Journal, 1962. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Defenders (of State Sovereignty and Individual Liberties), 1957-1962. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Desegregation Plan - Albemarle, undated. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Desegregation Plan - Clarke County, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Desegregation Plan - New Kent, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Desegregation Plan - Winchester, 1962. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Desegregation Plan - Health, Education, Welfare (HEW) A-K, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Desegregation Plan - Health, Education, Welfare (HEW) L-Pe., 1965. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Desegregation Plan - Health, Education, Welfare (HEW) Po.-Y and General Plans, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fiscal Records, 1957-1966. (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Graphs - Applications, 1961-1966. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Hidden" Test Scores - Harrisonburg, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Integrated Schools, undated. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Interview Questions, undated. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Job Dsecriptions, undated. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - King (application investigation), 1962. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Law Requests, 1957. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lawyer - Scott, Adolphus B., 1957-1964. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lease, 1957-1966. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Letters - Pro-Segregation, 1961-1966. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letters of Inquiry, 1957-1959. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letters of Inquiry - Parents, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Meeting - Superintendents, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Memorandums - Administrative, 1957-1960. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Memorandums - City Schools, 1962-1965. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Memorandums - County Scools A-L, 1962-1965. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Memorandums - County Schools M-W, 1962-1965. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Memorandums - Office, 1962-1965. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Memorandums - Private Schools, 1962-1965. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Memorandums to Division Superintendents, 1956-1965. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1966. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Model Letters, 1961. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Placement Policies of Other States, 1957. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Placement Procedures, undated. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Plans - Suggested, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Political Cartoon - Seibel, 1957. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Postal Regulations, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1956-1962. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Protests - Petersburg, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Private Schools List, undated. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Protest Chart, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Publicity for Board, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Report to Governor, 1957-1963. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Resolutions, 1958-1962. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Retirement, 1962-1966. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Return Student Figures, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Richmond City Schools List, undated. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Schedule, 1961-1963. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Statements by Board, undated. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Statistics - Desegregation, 1964-1965. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Statistics - Notes, 1957-1963. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Statistics - Published, 1962-1963. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Statistics - Reports, 1957-1966. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Superintendent Surveys, 1965-1966. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Suproco - Business Form Company, 1957-1964. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Test Scores - Henrico Schools, 1962. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II. State Agencies, 1957-1966., .35 cu. ft. (1 box) (Box 6)
    This subseries contains announcements from state agencies, the bulk of which are mass mailings.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by agency title.
    - Attorney General, 1964. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Auditor of Public Accounts, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Board of Education, 1964-1965. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Budget, Department of, 1958-1966. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Building and Grounds, 1964. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Comptroller, Office of, 1957-1961. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Office, 1957-1966. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Highway Safety Commission, 1963-1964. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - House of Delegates, 1960/1965. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Library of Virginia, 1964-1965. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Library of Virginia - Records Management Forms, 1961-1965. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Meetings, 1964-1965. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Personnel, Division of, 1957-1963. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Purchase and Supply, Department of, 1961-1966. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - State Corporate Commission, 1964-1966. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Statutory Research and Drafting, Division of, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Civil War Commission, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Supplemental Retirement Association, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council - Records Management, 1960/1965. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council - Retirement Policies, 1963. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Subseries III. City Applications, 1957-1966., 1.75 cu. ft. (5 boxes) (Box 7-12)
    The bulk of this subseries contains correspondence regarding Pupil Placement Board application forms, the majority of which are form memorandums from the board to the city listed on the folder in regard to the number student applications required to serve the area, or issues regarding a specified application. There is also correspondence concerning; specific students, placement issues within school districts, administrative transfers, and lists containing the names of students whose birth certificates were viewed.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically, thereunder chronologically.
    - Alexandria, 1958-1965. (Box 6 A, Folder 1-2)
    - Bristol, 1960-1966. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Buena Vista, 1962-1966. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Charlottesville, 1958-1960. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Chesapeake, 1963-1965. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Clifton Forge, 1963-1966. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Colonial Heights, 1962-1966. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Covington, 1962-1966. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Danville, 1962-1963. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Danville, 1964-1966. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Fairfax, 1963. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Franklin, 1964-1965. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Fredericksburg, 1960-1966. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Galax, 1959-1966. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Hampton, 1957-1961. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hampton, 1962. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Hampton, 1963-1965. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Harrisonburg, 1960-1966. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Harrisonburg - Madison College, 1964-1965. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Hopewell, 1960-1961. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hopewell, 1962-1966. (Box 8 A, Folder 1)
    - Lynchburg, 1959-1961. (Box 8 A, Folder 2)
    - Lynchburg, 1962-1964. (Box 8 A, Folder 3)
    - Martinsville, 1962-1966. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Newport News, 1958-1959. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk, 1960. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk, 1961-1965. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Norton, 1960-1966. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Petersburg, 1958-1961. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Petersburg, 1962. (Box 9 A, Folder 1)
    - Petersburg, 1963 Jan - July. (Box 9 A, Folder 2)
    - Petersburg, 1963 Aug - Dec. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Petersburg, 1964 Jan - June. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Petersburg, 1963 July - Dec. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Petersburg, 1965. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Petersburg, 1966. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Petersburg - Pending, 1964-1965. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Portsmouth, 1962. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Portsmouth, 1963-1964. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Portsmouth, 1965-1966. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Radford, 1960-1966. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Richmond, 1960-1961. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Richmond, 1962-1963. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Richmond, 1964-1966. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Roanoke, 1957-1960. (Box 11 A, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke, 1961. (Box 11 A, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke, 1962-1966. (Box 11 A, Folder 3)
    - South Boston, 1965-1966. (Box 11 A, Folder 4)
    - Soth Norfolk, 1960-1963. (Box 11 A, Folder 5)
    - Staunton, 1960-1966. (Box 11 A, Folder 6)
    - Suffolk, 1962-1965. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Beach, 1963-1965. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Beach - Chart, 1962-1964. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Waynesboro, 1961-1965. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Williamsburg - James City, 1962-1965. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Winchester, 1962-1966. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Suberies IV. County Applications, 1961-1966., 12 boxes (4.2 cu. ft.) (Box 12-24)
    The bulk of this subseries contains correspondence regarding Pupil Placement Board application forms, the majority of which are form memorandums from the board to the county listed on the folder in regard to the number student applications required to serve the area, or issues regarding a specified application. There is also correspondence concerning; specific students, placement issues within school districts, administrative transfers, and lists containing the names of students whose birth certificates were viewed.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by county name, thereunder chronologically.
    - Accomack, 1961-1965. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Albemarle, 1962-1965. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Alleghany, 1962-1966. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Amelia, 1962-1966. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Amherst, 1962-1965. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Appomattox, 1961-1966. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Arlington, 1957-1958. (Box 12 A, Folder 1)
    - Arlington, 1959-1961. (Box 12 A, Folder 2)
    - Arlington - Special File (1), 1958. (Box 12 A, Folder 3)
    - Arlington - Special File (2), 1958. (Box 12 A, Folder 4)
    - Arlington - Student and School Statistics, 1960. (Box 12 A, Folder 5)
    - Augusta, 1962-1966. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bath, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bedford, 1962-1966. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bland, 1962-1966. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Botetourt, 1962-1966. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Brunswick, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Buchanan, 1962. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Buckingham, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Caroline, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Carroll, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Charles City, 1962-1965. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Charlotte, 1962-1966. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Chesterfield, 1960-1961. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1962 Jan - Sept. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield, 1962 Oct - Nov. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Jan - Mar. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Apr - July. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Aug. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Sept. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Oct - Nov. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield, 1963 Dec. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield (Powhatan Transfers), 1963. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Jan. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Feb. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Mar. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Apr. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 May. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 June. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 July. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Aug. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Sept. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Oct. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Nov. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield, 1964 Dec. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Jan. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Feb. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Mar. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Apr. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 May. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 June. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 July. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Aug. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Sept. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Oct. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1965 Nov - Dec. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield (Longhair), 1965-1966. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield (Jan - Feb), 1966. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield (Mar - May), 1966. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield (Miscellaneous), undated. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Clarke, 1961-1966. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Culpeper, 1961-1966. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Cumberland, 1961-1965. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Cumberland - Civil Rights, 1965. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Dickenson, 1961-1966. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Dinwiddie, 1961-1965. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Essex, 1961-1965. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Fairfax, 1957-1959. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Fairfax, 1960-1965. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Fairfax - DeFebio Case, 1957-1958. (Box 19 A, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax - Special File, 1958. (Box 19 A, Folder 2)
    - Fauquier, 1961-1965. (Box 19 A, Folder 8)
    - Floyd, 1961-1966. (Box 19 A, Folder 9)
    - Floyd - Special File, 1959-1960. (Box 19 A, Folder 10)
    - Fluvanna, 1957-1965. (Box 19 A, Folder 11)
    - Franklin, 1961-1966. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Frederick, 1964-1966. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Giles, 1961-1966. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Gloucester, 1961-1966. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Goochland, 1961-1966. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Grayson, 1961-1966. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Greene - Madison, 1962-1965. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Greensville, 1962-1965. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Halifax, 1962-1966. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Hanover, 1962-1966. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Henrico, 1962. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Henrico, 1963-1966. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Henry, 1962-1965. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Highland, 1962-1966. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Isle of Wight, 1962-1965. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - King and Queen, 1962-1966. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - King George, 1962-1966. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - King William, 1961-1966. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Lancaster, 1962-1966. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Lee, 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Loudoun, 1961-1966. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Lunenburg, 1962-1965. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Louisa, 1962-1965. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Madison, 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Mathews, 1961-1966. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Mecklenburg, 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Middlesex, 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Montgomery, 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Nansemond, 1960-1965. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Nelson, 1962-1965. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - New Kent, 1962-1965. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk, 1962-1963. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Northampton, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Northumberland, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Nottoway, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Orange, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Page, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 8)